突然间发生了好多事
All of a sudden,so much is happening.
就是啊，罗斯要结婚
I know. Ross is getting married.
菲比在…做人
Phoebe's making people.
大家都在忙 只有我们坐在这里
-Everybody's doing stuff. -We just sit here.
要是我死了
If I died,people would know I was here...
大家只会从这张椅子的屁股印 知道我存在过
...only by the ass print on this chair!
我们要干嘛？ 浪费青春
-What are we doing? -Wasting our lives.
我是说午餐吃什么
I meant for lunch.
我们得做一件大事
We have to do something. Something huge!
我们可以去爬珠穆朗玛峰
We could climb Mt. Everest.
不是蠢事，是大事
Not something stupid. Something huge!
不，我在录影带上看到广告
I saw an ad for this video.
每天都有人在爬 我们也可以爬
People climb that thing every day. We could totally do that!
谁说不行？只不过是爬山
Why not? I mean,it's just climbing.
只不过很陡
-It's just steep! -Yeah.
我们去攻顶 在山顶留屁股印一定很爽
We're going! It'd be nice to leave an ass print on Everest.
在干什么？
What's up?
我们要去爬珠穆朗玛峰 没错
-We're gonna climb Mt. Everest. -Yeah,baby!
真的？我也去问过
I looked into that.
但是要花6万，而且可能会死
Yeah,but it costs like $60,000,and,you know,you could die.
你们一定会死
And you would die.
我们可以去借珠穆朗玛峰的录影带
We could get that Everest video.
对，那样就不必冒生命危险
We could do that without risking our lives at all.
到了录影带店 我们还可以借《虎胆龙威》
While we're at the video store,we could rent Die Hard!
我刚想到 那个录影带只能邮购
I just remembered.That Everest thing is only available through mail order.
所以你们要留下来陪我？ 对
So you'll stay here and hang out with me?
不过总有一天，我们会站起来
But one of these days...we'll get off our butts
再去借一次《虎胆龙威》
and rent Die Hard again!
本集播出：“邀请函”
The One with the lnvitation
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
真快，我通常要花2小时 才能让班乖乖睡觉
That was fast. It usually takes me hours to get Ben to go down for his nap.
他好可爱 你知道他刚才说什么？
He's such a sweetheart. Do you know what he said?
什么？ 妈咪，晚安
-Good night,mommy.
因为他有很多妈咪
-That's because he has lots of mommies.
那算是他对女人的通称
Yeah,in fact,it's kind of become his word for "woman".
怎样，请不请你的纳森叔叔？
So does your uncle Nathan get an invite or not?
没有人喜欢他
Oh,God! Nobody likes him.
而且他好小器 他绝不会飞去伦敦的
He's so cheap. He'd never fly to London in a million years.
好，请吧
Invite him!
我写得还可以吗？
Did I do these neat enough?
可以 是吗？
Yeah,they're fine.
别人问就说是班写的
We'll say that Ben addressed them.
你也请了瑞秋？
You invited Rachel then?
对啊，干嘛不请？
Sure,why not?
真的？
Really?
我找旧情人去一定会觉得别扭
I wouldn't be comfortable having any of my old lovers there.
你觉得我们不该请她吗？
Do you think we shouldn't invite her?
不，我很喜欢瑞秋，我只是…
You know I absolutely adore Rachel.It's just
怕你会尴尬，不过你决定就好
that I thought it might be awkward for you.But it's absolutely your decision.
还要茶吗？ 好
-More tea? -Sure.
伯爵（茶）？
Earl Grey?
好，你想请谁就请谁
Fine,invite whoever you want.
我不想单身，好吗？我想再婚
I don't want to be single,okay? I just want to be married again.
我想要1百万
And I just want a million dollars!
瑞秋？ 天哪，莫妮卡，谢天谢地
Oh God,Monica. Thank God!
各位，这是瑞秋 她也念林肯高中
This is Rachel. Another Lincoln High survivor.
这是钱德，菲比，乔伊
This is Chandler.Phoebe.Joey.
你记得我哥罗斯吗？ 当然记得
Do you remember Ross? -Sure.
你或许不知道，念高中时…
Back in high school...
我非常喜欢你
I had a major crush on you.
我知道 真的？
I knew.You did?
我以为你只当我是 莫妮卡的怪胎哥哥
I figured you thought I was Monica's geeky brother.
没错
I did.
你觉得…
Listen,do you think
请别被我容易紧张的缺点影响
Try not to let my intense vulnerability become a factor.
我改天可以约你出去吗？
Would it be okay if I asked you out sometime?
好啊…或许可以
Maybe.
好，或许我会约
Okay,maybe I will.
我看到你会有一段火热恋情
See,I see...big passion in your future.
真的？ 对
-Really? -I do.
罗斯，你真好
Ross,you're so great.
别做梦了
It's never gonna happen.
我想问个问题
I have a question.
其实不算是问题 比较算是一个疑惑…虑
Actually,it's not so much a question.It's more of a general wondering...ment.
其实我一直想要…
Well,for a while now,I've been wanting to....
对，没错
Yes,yes.That's right.
你看
Look!
什么？
What?
…世界的顶端，俯瞰万物
Top of the world looking Down on creation
我唯一能找到的解释
And the only explanation I can find
你给我听着 如果你要这辆车，就必须把我一块拖走
Listen,missy! If you want this cart,you'll have to take me with it!
你看到了吗？ 你太不可思议了
-Did you see that? -You were incredible!
你看到了吗？ 全新的瑞秋诞生了
A brand-new woman,ladies and gentlemen.
没有你我绝对办不到
I could not have done this without you.
好…烘干机里还有衣服吗？
More clothes in the dryer?
我没事
I'm fine.
你没资格说你对我有感觉
You had no right to tell me you had feelings for me.
什么？ 我和茱莉原本过得很好
I was doing great with Julie before I found out.
我原本过得也很好 你以为看你们在一起很好受吗
I was doing great too. It's not easy for me to see you with Julie.
重点是我不想要这样 好吗？来不及了
I don't need this right now.It's too late.
我有别人了，我很快乐 这艘船已经开了
I'm with somebody else. This ship has sailed!
好，你走啊
All right,fine! Go ahead and do that.
我不需要你这艘笨船
I don't need your stupid ship!
好 很好
Good,good
我这辈子第一次做我爱做的事
This is the first time I'm doing something I care about.
做我真正在行的事
I'm doing something that I'm actually good at.
要是你不懂…
If you don't get that
我懂，我很懂，我为你高兴 但我不想再跟答录机交往了
I get that,but I'm tired of your answering machine.
我已经没辄了 我也是
I don't know what to do.Neither do l!
跟马克有关吗？
Is this about Mark?
我的天哪 好，不是
Oh,my God!Okay,it's not.
我的天哪 我不能为了同样的事一吵再吵
I can't keep having this same fight over and over again.
你快把我逼疯了 好，我快把你逼疯了
You're making this too hard!
你要我怎么做？ 我不知道…
I am? What do you want me to do?I don't know.
也许我们应该分开
Look,maybe we should just take a break.
你说得对，我们先冷静一下
You're right. Let's cool off.
去吃点冷冻酸奶什么的
Let's get some frozen yogurt or something.
不，我是说分手
A break from us.
我们在赶什么？ 我昨晚提到的那个女朋友
-Why are we rushing? -The girlfriend I told you about.
她想跟我复合…找到了
She wants to get back together with me.I found it!
真是太好了
That's so great for you guys!
祝你复合成功 谢谢
-Good luck with your girlfriend. -Thank you.
瑞秋！
Rachel
你听到留言了吗？ 你真准时
-You got my message? -You are right on time.
我可以再当你的女朋友吗？
Can I be your girlfriend again?
可以得不得了
You can very much.
你给我走，滚
I want you to leave. Get out!
不，我想留下来谈一谈
I want to talk about this.
好，她怎么样？
All right,how was she?
什么？ 她厉害吗？
-What? -Was she good?
不要回答
Don't answer!
你说你想谈，那就谈啊 她怎么样？
You wanted to talk about it. How was she?
她…
She was....
很逊，什么也比不上你 不好
-She was not good,not good. -Nothing compared to you.
她不一样
She was different.
好的不一样？
Good different?
没有人喜欢改变
Nobody likes change.
别再说了
Just stop!
你这么坦然认错 证明你真的成长不少
The way you owned up to everything.It's just showed me how much you've grown,you know?
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
I mean,my mom never thought this would work out.
她说：欺骗一次就永远是个骗子
She was all,"Once a cheater,always a cheater."
真希望没有这4个月的空白
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
但要是时间能让你看清楚一点
But if time was what you needed just to gain a little perspective.
我们当时分手了！
We were on a break!
（瑞秋格林小姐收）
你似乎真的很喜欢她
You seem to really like her.
我能怎么办？ 我们说好只在一起2星期
What do I do? We agreed it'd be a two-week thing.
不要有承诺
No commitment.
那个女孩整晚都跟你的朋友 嚷着要听你的事
That girl just spent the entire evening talking to your friends...asking to hear stories about you
还看莫妮卡的相簿
...Iooking through Monica's photo albums.
只想在一起2周才不会这么做
You don't do that if you're just in it for two weeks.
是吗？
You think?
她还有14个小时才要去机场
You've got 14 hours until she has to be at the airport.
你却坐在走廊上 陪一个嘴肿起来的28岁的啦啦队长
And you're sitting here in a hallway...with a 28-year-old cheerleader with a fat lip.
你说得对
-You're right. -Yeah.
真好
This is so amazing!
我哥哥居然要去伦敦结婚 好浪漫喔
My brother's getting married and in London!It's so romantic.
真聪明，附面纸
Hey,pretty smart!Tissue paper.
参加婚礼当然会哭
You're at the wedding. You have to cry.
需要手帕吗？不了，我有喜帖
Handkerchief? No,I got my invitation.
真可爱，罗斯让班写我的信封
Isn't this adorable?Ross let Ben address mine.
你收到罗斯的喜帖了吗？ 没有
Did you get your invitation to Ross' wedding?No.
放心，我可以带一位亲友 看他怎么说
Don't worry,I get to bring a guest. We'll show him.
好嫉妒你们都要去 怀孕第三个三月居然不能坐飞机
I'm so jealous you're all going.I never knew you can't fly in your third trimester.
我也不知道
I didn't,either.
我知道
I knew that.
我不知道，但你们的表情好妙
So I didn't know that. But you should see your faces.
你们在干嘛？
What's up?
也没干嘛
Just hanging out.
这是什么？罗斯的喜帖？
What's this? Ross' wedding invitation?
也许该藏的是那一张
Maybe that's the one we should have hidden.
不，不必那样 我很替他高兴
No,you guys,come on. You don't have to do that.I'm happy for him.
真的，我很…
I am. I really
我会调适的
I'll work on it.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不过你会去吧？
You're going to come,though,aren't you?
我不知道
I don't know.
该不会她不去我们就不去吧？ 我已经买票了
This isn't one of those "lf she doesn't come,we don't come"?
他根本没请你
-I bought my ticket. -You're not even invited.
你不去会很奇怪
You know what would be real weird? If you weren't there.
你就考虑一下吧 我会的
-Just say you'll think about it. -I'll think about it.
这是谁送的？ 罗斯送的
-Who's this from? -That's Ross'.
天哪
Oh,my God!
他记得 记得什么？
He remembered.Remembered what?
好几个月前 我们经过一家古董店
It was months ago. We were walking by this antique store.
我看到这个别针对他说 小时我奶奶有一个一模一样的
I saw this and told him it was like one my grandmother had...when I was a little girl.
他居然记得
I can't believe he remembered!
他一定花了很多钱 他居然这么大方
This must've cost a fortune.I can't believe he did this.
记得他大学爱上卡萝时 就送了她一只超贵的水晶鸭
Remember when he fell in love with Carol...and got her that expensive crystal duck?
你刚才说什么？
What did you just say?
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
来自北京的457号班机 刚刚抵达
Flight number 457 from Beijing now arriving.
天哪
Oh,my God!
我们是老同学 毕业后就没见过
-We were in school together. -We haven't seen each other since.
到了中国 你们猜是谁主持挖掘工作？
I land in China. Guess who's in charge of the dig?
茱莉
Julie!
很棒吧？
Isn't that great?
感觉就像踢断你的腿扭断你的脖子
Isn't that just kick-you-in-the-crotch,spit-on-your-neck fantastic?
你真好
That is so sweet!
不…不，你先挂
No,you hang up.
不，你…好 一，二，三
No,you One,two,three.
你也没挂 她也没挂
You didn't hang up!She didn't hang up either.
不，你挂 你挂，你挂…
Okay,no. No,you hang up.You!
罗斯，嗨，我是瑞秋
Ross,hi.It's Rachel.
我只是打来告诉你一切都很好
I'm just calling to say that everything's fine.
我很替你和你的猫高兴
And I'm really happy for you...and your cat.
所以显然的，我已经放下你了
Obviously,I am over you.
我已经放下你了
I am over you.
而那样，就是所谓的了结
And that,my friend,is what they call closure.
瑞秋，有你的留言
I got a message from you.
完了，罗斯，挂掉 电话给我…
Oh,my God! Hang up the phone!Give me the phone
你放下我了？ 天哪
You're over me?Oh,God.
你放下我了？你什么时候…
You're over me?When were you...
在意我的？
...under me?
基本上…最近…我…
Basically...Iately,I've....
我有点对你有感觉
I've sort of had feelings for you.
好，我得躺下
I need to lie down.
他跟茱莉分手了
He broke up with Julie!
过去抱她啊
Go hug her,for God's sakes!
真的？ 真的
-Really? -Really.
我一直都只要你 天哪
It's always been you,Rach.Oh,God.
抱歉今晚还得工作
Listen,I'm sorry I had to work tonight.
没关系，你值得我等
That's okay.You're worth the wait.
我不只是指今晚
And I don't just mean tonight.
天哪
Oh,God!
亲爱的，没关系
Honey.That's okay.
不是，你压到果汁了
No,you just rolled over the juice box.
甘瑟，你没告诉瑞秋 我跟影印店女生的事吧？
Did you say anything to Rachel about me and the girl from the copy place?
对不起，我不该说吗？
I'm sorry.Was I not supposed to?
是你要分手的
You ended it!
因为我很气你 不是因为我不爱你了
Because I was mad at you. Not because I stopped loving you.
你还爱我？ 没有
You still love me?
什么意思？你想复合吗？
What does this mean? Do you want to get back together?
不是…也许吧
Maybe.
我不… 什么？
I don't know.
我只是觉得…
I just,I feel....
我居然会想跟你复合 我们根本就完了
I can't believe I even thought of getting back together. We're so over!
无所谓
Fine by me!
顺便告诉你 这种事并不常见
And hey! Just so you know,it's not that common.
并非男人都会这样 这是很严重的
It doesn't happen to every guy,and it is a big deal.
我就知道
I knew it!
瑞秋来了，她是不是很美啊？
Rachel's coming up. Doesn't she look pretty?
天哪 这是我们准备要去参加舞会
Oh,my God!This is us getting ready for the prom.
这种带子就别看了
We don't have to watch this.
当然要看 拜托啦
Yeah,we do!Come on!
拍一下莫妮卡 怎么拉远？
-Get a shot of Monica. -How do you zoom out?
有了
There she is!
闭嘴，上镜头会多10磅
Shut up! The camera adds 10 pounds.
所以是有几个镜头对着你？
So how many cameras are actually on you?
爸，关掉啦
Dad,turn it off!
我关了，对吧，罗斯？
It is off.Right,Ross?
很帅喔，科特尔先生（《欢迎科特尔先生归来》中的角色）
Looking good,Mr. Kotter!
我没舞伴不能去舞会 时间来不及了
I can't go to my prom without a date. It's too late.
要是你不去，我也不想去了
If you're not going,then I don't want to go either.
我有个好主意 你带瑞秋去参加舞会
I have a wonderful idea.You should take Rachel to the prom.
看够了，关掉吧 不要啦
We've seen enough. Let's turn it off.
那我不看，行吧？
-I want to see! -Fine,I'm not going to watch.
走吧
Come on,kid. Let's go.
你好帅 去让他们瞧瞧
Are you handsome!Let's show them!
行了 瑞秋，不管你好了没
-Okay,Dad. -Rachel,ready or not.
解救你的白马王…糟了
Here comes your knight in shining
天哪…要怎么关掉？
Oh,dear!How do I turn this off?
你居然这样做 我就…
I can't believe you did that.Yeah,well....
看吧，他是她的龙虾
See? He's her lobster!
不会吧…你真的不去？
No.You're really not going?
对，我会很难面对
It's just going to be too hard.
毕竟…他是罗斯
You know,I mean...it's Ross.
我怎么能看着他结婚？
How can I watch him get married?
这样最好，真的
It's just for the best. You know? It is.
而且总得有人陪菲比 到时她的肚子会很大
Plus somebody's got to stay here with Phoebe.She's going to be pretty big by then.
她会需要别人绑鞋带
She'll need someone to help her tie her shoes.
在她要生的时候送她去医院
Drive her to the hospital if she goes into labor.
你没有车，驾照也过期了
You don't have a car.And your license expired.
看吧，事情那么多 时间却那么少
There's so much to do,and I have so little time!
你们看 这里有完整的博物馆录影带
Check this out.There's a place you can go to rent videos of all the museums.
“几乎如同身历其境”
"It's almost as good as being there."
太好了，去博物馆不能只穿内裤
It's better! You can't go to a museum in your underwear.
可以，但之后你会被封杀
You could,but just the one time.
我们可以去租景点录影带
We could get videos of the sights...
搬台录放影机就不必出旅馆房间了
...get a VCR in our hotel room and never have to go outside!
那一定要租《虎胆龙威》
-lf we do that,we've got to rent Die Hard.
英国版一定很棒
-I bet the British version is good!